Contact

marksirany@me.com

www.linkedin.com/in/mark-tsirany-73360965 (LinkedIn) marksirany.github.io/profile3/ (Portfolio) github.com/marksirany (Other)

Top Skills

Editing

Microsoft Office

Project Management

Languages

Spanish

English

Honors-Awards

Recognition of Placement on the Dean's List and Superior Academic Performance

Mark T. Sirany

Coding Boot Camp at University of Minnesota

Minneapolis, Minnesota

Summary

Check out my online portfolio here: https://marksirany.github.io/profile3/

I am starting a new career as a Full Stack Web Developer after over 10 years as a technical writer. I am currently enrolled in full time coding bootcamp at the University of Minnesota. I have career experience in web design with Valmont Industries and Plumbline Builders of Minnesota.

I designed, managed, and updated Valmont's Irrigation Division international product documentation website and managed the content database for the domestic product documentation website. This required continuous translation management and updating into 16 languages. I also designed and wrote content for Plumbline Builders of Minnesota's website.

I have worked with senior engineers, service technicians, product managers, and marketing teams to write owner's manuals, service manuals, installation manuals, and product guides for irrigation machinery, machine control panels, control panel software and hardware, network connectivity, and communication systems.

I have a Bachelor of Arts degree in English specializing in American Literature from the University of Nebraska at Omaha.

Experience

Xigent Solutions
Technical Writer
September 2018 - September 2019 (1 year 1 month)
Plymouth, Minnesota

Developed Content Plan and Process:

- -Developed internal content plan including workflow and processes that facilitated the creation of consistent and accurate statement of work for client engagements.
- -Developed and maintained a library of technical content through the creation and implementation of company document repository.

Managed Process:

-Worked with the Sales Team to plan, develop, organize, write and edit SOWs for customer projects.

Plumbline Builders of Minneapolis Senior Web Designer / Website Manager 2018 - 2019 (1 year)

Greater Minneapolis-St. Paul Area

- -Designed and managed company website
- Social media manager
- -Marketing and Advertising Manager

Avionte Staffing Software
Digital Content Writer
April 2018 - June 2018 (3 months)

Eagan, Minnesota

- -Wrote engaging content for campaigns and use across a number of channels
- -Developed, optimized, and posted original content, including but not limited to collateral, website, blogs, ads, social, email, and a variety of value-add content pieces
- -Managed all digital and print. Including writing, editing, proofing, and ensuring all content is SEO optimized
- -Worked with digital marketing to optimize content based on analytics and made recommendations to improve performance
- -Help develop, communicate, and execute content plans and social campaigns
- -Updated and maintained all content across the sales team

Conductix-Wampfler USA
Marketing Journalist and Technical Writer
May 2017 - May 2018 (1 year 1 month)
Omaha, NE

Marketing Journalist and Engineering Technical Writer

• Shared service position working for both marketing department and engineering department.

- Work Assignments Included: Job Application Stories and Job Reference Summaries, Web Site Copy, Press Releases, Newsletter articles, Advertising copy for technical publications, Catalog and brochure copy, Video Scripts, and Instruction, Operations, and Maintenance Manuals
- Personally responsible for creating and implementing a new documentation review process for the engineering department.
- Personally responsible for creating and implementing a new standard design for all engineering documentation.

Hive Media
Digital Content Writer
July 2016 - February 2017 (8 months)

Content writer for online articles and publications.

Valmont Industries, Inc.
Project Manager / Technical Writer / Illustrator
October 2012 - October 2015 (3 years 1 month)
Valley, NE

- Designed, managed, and updated Valmont Irrigation Division's international product documentation website.
- Managed the content database for Valmont Irrigation Division's domestic product documentation website.
- Created and managed the process for the international translation of product manuals into 16 languages (coordinated product/engineering change management of over 400 documents).
- Technical writer and illustrator of owner's manuals and product manuals for electronic control panels, user interface testing and member of mechanical, electronic, software engineering product team.
- Over 103 projects successfully completed and implemented during employment
- Coordination specialist for field service documentation used for product installation and training.

NAGL MANUFACTURING CO Technical Writer May 2012 - August 2012 (4 months) Greater Omaha Area

- Responsible for the creation of new work instructions and flow charts across multiple departments
- Digital photographic documentation of on site production processes

Demand Studios
Digital Content Writer
2009 - 2012 (3 years)

Freelance writer of instructional articles

Ehow.com
Digital Content Writer
2009 - 2012 (3 years)

• Freelance writer of instructional articles

American Indians In Unity, Inc. (Non-profit Organization)
Writing Internship
2005 - 2006 (1 year)

- Responsible for creating the financial management course booklet for both the instructor and students
- Created PowerPoint presentations used for classroom instruction

Zoo Press Writing Internship 2004 - 2005 (1 year)

- Proofreading and pre-production responsibilities
- Data entry and manuscript review for the Paris and Kenyon Review Prizes in Poetry
- General administrative responsibilities

Education

University of Minnesota Coding Boot Camp · (2019 - 2020)

University of Michigan

Master's degree, Information Science/Studies · (2017 - 2019)

University of Nebraska at Omaha

Bachelor's Degree, English specializing in American Literature · (2013 - 2016)